hey everybody welcome to this a2
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak remember to
sign up for our one dollar
listening practice seminars at
polyglossa.com
and download our free listening time
podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about
motivation
this is a useful topic because we all
need motivation
to do things in our lives first let's
talk about
motivation in general if we have
motivation this means that we have a
desire
to do something if we lack this
then it's much harder to actually
accomplish things
most of us feel motivated at times
but unmotivated at other times
this is perfectly normal there are
certain days when you don't
feel like doing much you might be tired
in a bad mood or just uninterested
i sometimes feel this way when i have to
do
certain things for example i might not
be
super motivated to work or to do my
language learning for the day
i think we all have times when we're
more
and less motivated to do things
so let's talk about some ways we can get
motivated
i think the most important thing we need
to do
to find our motivation is to set
long-term
goals these goals are things that you
really want to accomplish they can be
personal goals
or professional goals once you have
these goals in mind
you can create a plan to reach these
goals
some people make very detailed plans
and some people are a little more
flexible with their plans
in my opinion it's good to set
short-term goals
that will help you reach your long-term
goals
and more importantly all of these goals
should be
time specific for example i could make
my long-term goal
to become fluent in french in two years
and then maybe i could make a short-term
goal for
six months one year and a year and a
half from now
that will help me reach that two-year
goal
if you set specific deadlines for your
goals
this can help motivate you because you
can see
the finish line another thing that can
help
motivate you is to imagine yourself
in the future after you've already
completed your goal
for example if you have the goal to
speak
english fluently imagine yourself in the
future
speaking english fluently imagine what
that will feel like
and imagine the satisfaction it will
give you
i find that this motivates me a lot
sometimes when i'm doing something
i think why am i doing this what's the
point
but if i imagine how it will feel when i
accomplish my goal
in the future this helps me continue
another way you can increase your
motivation
is by finding the right place and time
to do your task
personally i feel more motivated to work
in certain spaces in my apartment and i
feel less motivated in other spaces
it's pretty interesting actually also i
feel really motivated to work or
study when i go to cafes when i'm
surrounded by
other people who are working or reading
it motivates me to do this too also
it's important to identify the time of
day
when you feel most motivated you should
use this time period to accomplish as
much as possible
thus it's important to plan your day so
that you can take advantage of this time
in general i know the hours when i'm
motivated to work
and when i'm usually tired so i plan my
day with this in mind
one last thing that can also motivate
you
is finding a role model a role model
is someone who you look to for
inspiration
specifically it's good to find a role
model
who has already accomplished what you're
trying to accomplish
for example if you want to move up in
your career
you can find a role model who has
already reached a high
level in your industry you can learn
from their success
and you can follow in their footsteps as
we say
having a role model can motivate you to
work hard
and not give up alright now i'm going to
ask you some questions about today's
video
to see how well you understood number
one
what types of goals should we set number
two
what's one place where i feel motivated
to work or study
and number three what's a role model
okay remember to sign up for our one
dollar listening practice seminars
and download the listening time podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
also subscribe to the channel click on
the bell and follow us on instagram
i'll see you next time
you